#### THOMAS M. CLAYDON

# Full Stack Software/Mechanical Engineer

tomclaydon102@gmail.com | 914-522-8809 | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

Professional Full Stack Web Developer (2+ years). Prior experience in mechanical engineering (2+ years) working as a HVAC/Plumbing design engineer and (10+ years) in the construction industry as Laborer, Drafter, and Manager. Offering flexible technical and management skills suited for a dynamic working environment and a strong willingness to take on new languages and technical topics.

# PROGRAMMING TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Tailwinds, Material UI, JavaScript, React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, Express, PostgresSQL, SQLite, knex.js, jestjs.js, Heroku, Netlify, GCP, GIT, Postman, NPM, Python, C++, C

#### **EXPERIENCE**

C Hear September 2019 - October 2020

Full Stack Web Developer/Software Engineer

- Developed Technology Demonstration.
- Designed and Developed Full Stack Management Rest Application for Production
- Managed/Developed Internal Services
- Contributed to Core Technology

## Lambda School Academy of Computer Science and Web Development

March - April 2019

Teaching Assistant - Web Development

- Acted as a medium between the class instructor and team members, providing materials, references, guidelines and instruction when required.
- Provided over watch during the project duration, spotting pitfalls regarding teammate miscommunication, and improper or poorly thought out solutions. Responded with precise guidelines in order to steer them in a productive direction.
- Helped solve looming problems associated with deployment, database/server architecture and version control.
- Oversaw daily standup meetings for 10+ students to facilitate communication between the team members, providing the opportunity to speak out about concerns or problems regarding the project state.

### Rose Wood Shop, Portchester, NY

May. 2016 - Present

Drafter/Estimator

- Served as the project drafter creating detailed shop drawings for custom cabinet manufacturing.
- Acted as a project estimator, reviewed architectural drawings and calculated pricing for project proposals.

# Collado Engineering, White Plains, NY

Sept. 2014 - Oct. 2016

Mechanical/Plumbing/Fire Protection Consulting Engineer

- Served as a project manager and engineer to manage teams of 3+ engineers in a fast-paced working environment.
- Produced complete designs of mechanical, plumbing and fire protection building systems in the Tri State Area.
- Collaborated with owners, architects, building officials, and contractors to provide these solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

### Lambda School Academy of Computer Science and Web Development

Oct. - July 2019

Lambda School is a 9+ month Software Engineering Academy that provides an immersive hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, software engineering, and web development.

- Approached coding challenges with and without pair programming.
- Utilized agile software development and Git workflow on all projects.
- Gained hands-on experience with client and server testing,
- Completed all curriculum course work including: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Node, Express, Python, C
- Wrote production-ready code using React, Redux, Node and Express to build single page applications.

Manhattan College, Riverdale, NY

B.S. Mechanical Engineering

Sept. 2010 - May 2014